Benjamin Huffman

1211 Barbosa Lane, Cary, NC, 27518 * (252) 939-5698 * BenjaminD.Huffman@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Ambitious systems analyst, coding bootcamp graduate, and full time computer science student with a passion for people, learning, and technology. Seeking to leverage experience as part of an agile team, 9+ years of customer service, and full-stack web development certification to begin a career in software development.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

NCSECU, Raleigh, NC

Systems Analyst, May 2022 - Present

- Work closely with a team of developers to ensure software meets business requirements and to communicate necessary changes to upcoming software builds throughout the development life cycle.
- Perform user acceptance and systems integration testing for all incoming software changes for a fleet of 1200+ ATM terminals.
- Ensure uptime and availability of North Carolina's largest ATM network through close monitoring and dispatching of technicians.
- Oversee and document hardware/software changes and business requirements pertaining to ATM systems.
- Organize, analyze, and present data regarding impacts of projects to terminal availability and resource usage.
- Follow standards of an agile workforce and maintain records of all completed and ongoing tickets and tasks.
- Lead weekly remote presentations to deliver updates on project status to internal departments and third party vendors.

TARGET, Cary, NC

Fulfillment Operations Team Lead, July 2021 - May 2022

Designated Business Owner, September 2019 - July 2021

- Promoted to management within 2 years for exceeding performance goals, promoting company culture, and assuming a leadership role in interdepartmental communications, the training of new hires, and the delegation of tasks.
- Oversaw the daily operations of a high-volume retail fulfillment department originating \$10M+ in sales annually.
- Managed a team of 30+ team members through effective scheduling, hiring, and policy enforcement.
- Acted as a liaison between upper management and team members to effectively communicate policy changes and team member needs.
- Guaranteed the on-time fulfillment and shipment of 1500+ daily orders through close partnerships with multiple logistics carriers.
- Utilized metrics and market trends to successfully navigate real-world impacts to logistics, supply chains, and business volume

NC SPACE GRANT HIGH-ALTITUDE BALLOONING COMPETITION, Winterville, NC

Paid research experience Feb 2018 - April 2018

- Followed the NASA design cycle to design, prototype, test, and launch an experiment on board a high-altitude payload.
- Utilized and built upon existing C++ knowledge to develop software for microcontroller driven sensors, cameras, and wireless communications arrays.
- Worked closely with a team of budding engineers and computer scientists to deliver a complete product from scratch.
- Led monthly remote presentations to communicate progress and results to the competition board.

EDUCATION

PITT COMMUNITY COLLEGE - Winterville, NC

Associate of Science Chemistry (May 2018)

EAST CAROLINA UNIVERSITY - Greenville, NC

Completed coursework towards Bachelor of Science (B.S.) Chemistry (Jul 2018)

MICHIGAN STATE UNIVERSITY - East Lansing, MI (Remote)

Completed 24 Week Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp — Certification (Sep 2022)

SOUTHERN NEW HAMPSHIRE UNIVERSITY - Manchester, NH (Remote)

Currently enrolled - Bachelor of Science (B.S.) Computer Science (Aug 2022 - Present)

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Experience working as part an agile team.
- Solid foundation with Power BI data visualization software and Microsoft Office suite.
- Familiarity with Software/Systems Design Lifecycle
- Fostering professional relations with third-party vendors, carriers, and service providers.
- Experience with React.js, MySQL and MongoDB, Express.js, and Node.js creating full-stack applications.